# **GUILHERME ALMEIDA**

# Senior Software Engineer • Web and Mobile Developer

- · linkedin.com/in/jgoa156
- jgoa156@gmail.com
- github.com/jgoa156
- · +55 92 98465-6666



### **SUMMARY**

Senior Software Engineer with 6 years of experience in web development, specializing in React, Next.js, Node.js and Java. Proven track record in front-end optimization and API design with successful projects for Banco do Brasil, CVC and SAP.

# **LANGUAGES**

• English: Fluent • Portuguese: Native

## SOFT SKILLS

- Creative Adaptable Problem solver
- Highly communicative

# HARD SKILLS

### FRONTEND

- React
  TypeScript
  Next.js
  Styled Components
- React Native
- Design UI/UX design Adobe CC Figma
- Unit Testing Jest JUnit

### BACKEND

- Node.js Express.js Sequelize Nest.js
- Prisma
- Python Django Scrapy Pytesseract Pandas
- Java
  Spring Boot
  Spring MVC

### **OTHERS**

- Databases MySQL PostgreSQL MongoDB
- Software Architecture Design Patterns
- Atomic Design
  Microsservices
  REST
- Others Agile Methodologies Docker AWS
- · CI/CD

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### HCL Tech - Senior Full Stack Engineer - October 2024 - Present

- Maintained SAP's legacy codebase (JavaScript & ASP)
- Reduced technical debt and fixed CSP issues
- Accessibility and performance corrections
- Updated dependencies
- · Worked with international, multicultural team

#### Betablocks - Full Stack Engineer - January 2024 - July 2024

- · Built Web3 apps with Python (Django) and React
- Integrated blockchains, crypto payments, and cloud services
- Led UI/UX design for seamless user experiences

#### loasys - Front-end developer - April 2022 - February 2023

- Built CVC's bus ticket platforms, Rodofácil and Rodoviário Exclusivo
- Used TypeScript, React, Jest, and Docker
- Participated in war room before launch to ensure a smooth release

#### Capgemini - Full Stack developer - June 2021 - April 2022

- Helped develop Banco do Brasil's investments page
- · Worked on front-end using React, Next.js, and CI/CD pipelines
- Contributed to UI/UX design for a better user experience

#### CREA-AM - Full Stack developer - May 2019 - June 2021

- Developed on-demand software with React, Wordpress, PHP, Node, Java, and Python
- Designed full-stack apps from scratch, handling UI/UX and deployment (FTP)
- Automated tasks and performed web scraping using Python and Scrapy

# **EDUCATION**

Federal University of Amazonas - Software Engineering - Bachelor's Degree - January 2019 - March 2024

Federal Institute of Amazonas - Informatics - Technical Degree - February 2016 - December 2018

State University of Amazonas - Embedded Android Development - Certificate Course - January 2021 - May 2021

**GRACOM** - Graphic Design - Certificate Course - May 2016 - July 2017